Grace Kara Situmorang

Pamulang Permai N7/1, RT 006/ RW 005, Pamulang Barat, Tangerang 15417
Email :gracekara89@gmail.com
id.linkedin.com/in/gracekarasitumorang
Mobile Phone: +62 821 23677 557
Date of Birth: Jakarta, September 8th 1988



Summary

Kara is a dynamic team leader; able to bring energy and enthusiasm to motivate team members to achieve potential and meet objectives.

Having years of experience as a Procurement, Kara is now pursuing her career in digital as an Account Manager, allowing her to have two perspectives as a client and also as a vendor.

Education

2009

2014-Present Master of Social Science

University of Indonesia - Depok, Indonesia

International Relations GPA 3.43 out of 4.00

2008 - 2013 Bachelor of Economics

Prasetiya Business School - Jakarta, Indonesia

Business Management

Activities & Awards

2015	Jakarta Model United Nations, ISAFIS, Jakarta
2015	Conference on Indonesia Foreign Policy – As a Top 4 Essay Finalists, Jakarta
2012	Best Value Award – Proactive Category, People Appreciation Day, PT Sumberdaya Sewatama
2011	Community Development Project, Desa Babakan Sari, Cianjur, Indonesia.
2010	Attended "Equilibrium: Persilangan Pasar dan Idealisme" Seminar, Prasetiya Mulya Business School
2010	Attended "Psychology and Trading Strategy" Seminar by Courtney Smith, Prasetiya Mulya Business School

Participated in "Liga Prasmul" as a leader in Women's Day Division, Prasetiya Mulya

Business School

Language& Computer Skills

- Bahasa Indonesia Native
- English Fluent (IELTS Band: 7.00 out of 9.00)
- Microsoft Office (Microsoft Word, Excel, Powerpoint, Outlook)
- SAP Material Management Module

Work Experience

May 2016 - Present Account Manager

Customer Excellence Team, GetCRAFT, Jakarta, Indonesia

Duties: As the lead of Customer Excellence Tool Team to take over the confirmed project from BD team and assign to Account Executive – then Production and Creators, communicate feedback to the creative team and clearly articulating next steps, distribute as quickly as possible (1-hour turnaround) to all team members, partner with Account Executives to handle seamless internal workflow and development of project schedules and delivering reports.

Project lead for: General Electrics, Wego Tourism Australia, Blibli, Commonwealth, Smartfren #Generasi4G, Philippines Department of Tourism, etc.

Jan 2016 - Apr 2016 Senior Account Executive

Customer Excellence Team, GetCRAFT, Jakarta, Indonesia

Duties: Handle the day-to-day management of clients' advertising campaigns, ensure the quality of the project's output (creative, timeline, results reporting), completing projects to a specific schedule and within an agreed budget, regular communication and liaison with clients and supervise Junior Account Executive Team in running their projects, including the interns, as well.

Project lead for: GO-JEK Saves The Date, AXA, Schneider Sustainability Campaign, OPPO F1, Nibble App, etc.

Apr 2015 - Jan 2016

Procurement Specialist/ Supplier Quality Engineer

Supply Chain Management Department, PT Sumberdaya Sewatama (Tiara Marga Trakindo Group), Jakarta, Indonesia

As a dedicated procurement specialist for Energy Efficiency Service, one of Sewatama's Line of Business (LoB).

Duties: Providing users' needs for parts, materials or services, liaison with suppliers for RFQs and competitive pricing, product evaluation duties and budgets, delivery arrangements, updating and maintaining supplier contract database and auditing invoice

versus supplier contract rates.

Sep 2012 - Mar 2015

Procurement Strategic Planner

Supply Chain Management Department, PT Sumberdaya Sewatama (Tiara Marga Trakindo Group), Jakarta, Indonesia

Duties: Analyzing spareparts and material forecasts, monitoring suppliers' performance, implementing new or improved supply chain processes and supporting users' needs.

Projects: PLTD Projects in Java, Kalimantan and Sumatera.

Jan - July 2012

Learning & Development Intern

Human Resource Department, PT Sumberdaya Sewatama (Tiara Marga Trakindo Group), Jakarta, Indonesia

Duties: Ensuring statutory training requirements are met, working with line managers in producing training materials and working in a team to produce programmes that are satisfactory to all relevant parties.

July - Sep 2010

English Tutor

AIESEC Global Exchange Program, Izmir, Turkey

Duties: Planning, preparing and delivering lessons, setting tests, examinations papers and exercises and providing feedback on oral and written work.

July - Aug 2009

Human Resource & Finance Intern

Lapindo Brantas, Inc., Jakarta, Indonesia

Duties: Input training records of the employees, sorting employees' invoices for reimbursement process and filing employees' insurance claim record.